JOHN EWALD: Hello, and welcome to Introduction
JOHN EWALD：大家好，欢迎来到大型语言模型介绍课程。
My name is John Ewald, and I'm a training developer here
我是JOHN EWALD，谷歌云的培训开发人员。
In this course, you learn to define large language
在这门课程中，您将学习定义大型语言模型，
models, or LLMs, describe LLM use cases,
即LLM，描述LLM的用例，
explain prompt tuning, and describe Google's Gen AI
解释提示调优（Prompt Tuning），以及介绍谷歌的Gen AI开发工具。
Large language models, or LLMs, are a subset of deep learning.
大型语言模型，即LLM，是深度学习的一个子集。
To find out more about deep learning,
想了解更多关于深度学习的信息，
see our Introduction to Generative AI course video.
请观看我们的生成式AI课程视频。
LLMs and generative AI intersect and they are
LLMs和生成式AI相交，它们都是
both a part of deep learning.
深度学习的一部分。
Another area of AI you may be hearing a lot about
你可能经常听到的另一个AI领域
This is a type of artificial intelligence that
这是一种能够
can produce new content, including text, images, audio,
生成新内容的人工智能，包括文本、图像、音频、
and synthetic data.
和合成数据。
So what are large language models?
那么大型语言模型是什么？
Large language models refer to large general-purpose language
大型语言模型是指可以预先训练，然后进行微调
models that can be pre-trained and then fine
以适应特定目的的大型通用语言模型。
Imagine training a dog.
想象一下训练一条狗。
These commands are normally sufficient for everyday life
这些命令对日常生活来说足够了
and help your dog become a good canine citizen.
帮助你的狗成为一个好的犬类公民。
However, if you need a special service dog such as a police
但是，如果你需要特殊服务犬，比如警犬、
dog, a guide dog, or a hunting dog, you add special trainings.
导盲犬或猎犬，你需要增加特殊训练。
The similar idea applies to large language models.
这个概念也适用于大型语言模型。
These models are trained for general purposes
这些模型是为通用目的而训练的
to solve common language problems such as text
解决常见的语言问题，如文本分类、问答、
summarization, and text generation across industries.
文档摘要和跨行业的文本生成。
Let's further break down the concept
我们进一步分解这个概念，
into three major features of large language models.
将其分为大型语言模型的三个主要特点。
Large indicates two meanings.
大有两层含义。
First is the enormous size of the training data set,
首先是训练数据集的庞大规模，
Second, it refers to the parameter count.
其次，它指的是参数数量。
In ML, parameters are often called hyperparameters.
在机器学习中，参数通常被称为超参数。
Parameters are basically the memories and the knowledge
参数基本上是机器从模型训练中学到的记忆和知识。
Parameters define the skill of a model
参数定义了模型在解决问题（如预测文本）的技能。
are sufficient to solve common problems.
足以解决常见问题。
Two reasons lead to this idea.
有两个原因导致了这个想法。
First is the commonality of a human language regardless
首先是人类语言的共性，无论
And second is the resource restriction.
其次是资源限制。
Only certain organizations have the capability
只有某些组织具备能力
to train such large language models with huge data sets
用大量数据集训练这种大型语言模型
and a tremendous number of parameters.
和大量参数。
How about letting them create fundamental language models
让他们为其他人创建基本语言模型怎么样？
This leads to the last point, pre-trained and fine tuned,
这导致了最后一点，预训练和微调，
meaning to pre-train a large language
意味着用大型数据集预训练一个通用目的的大型语言模型
and then fine tune it for specific aims with a much
然后用更小的数据集为特定目标进行微调。
The benefits of using large language models
使用大型语言模型的好处很明显。
First, a single model can be used for different tasks.
首先，一个模型可以应用于不同的任务。
This is a dream come true.
这是梦想成真。
These large language models that are
这些经过大量数据训练并生成数十亿参数的大型语言模型
of parameters are smart enough to solve different tasks,
足够智能，能解决不同的任务，
including language translation, sentence completion, text
包括语言翻译、句子补全、文本分类、问答等。
Second, large language models require minimal field training
其次，当你定制大型语言模型来解决特定问题时，
data when you tailor them to solve your specific problem.
它们需要的领域训练数据很少。
Large language models obtain decent performance
大型语言模型表现不错
In other words, they can be used for few shot or even
换句话说，它们可用于少量样本（Few-shot）甚至零样本（Zero-shot）场景。
In machine learning, few shot refers
在机器学习中，少样本是指
to training a model with minimal data,
用最少的数据训练模型，
and zero shot implies that a model can recognize
而零样本意味着模型能识别
things that have not explicitly been taught in the training
在以前的训练中未明确教过的事物。
Third, the performance of large language models
第三，大型语言模型的性能
is continuously growing when you add more data and parameters.
随着数据和参数的增加而不断提高。
Let's take PaLM as an example.
以PaLM为例。
In April 2022, Google released PaLM,
2022年4月，谷歌发布了PaLM，
short for Pathways Language Model, a 540 billion-parameter
简称Pathways Language Model，这是一个拥有5400亿参数的模型，
PaLM is a dense decoder-only transformer model.
PaLM是一个仅解码器的密集型Transformer模型，
It leverages the new pathways system,
它利用了新的路径系统，
which has enabled Google to efficiently
这使得谷歌能够在多个TPU V4集群上有效地训练一个模型。
Pathway is a new AI architecture that
Pathway是一种新的AI架构，它可以
will handle many tasks at once, learn new tasks quickly,
同时处理多个任务，快速学习新任务，
and reflect a better understanding of the world.
并更好地理解世界。
The system enables PaLM to orchestrate distributed
该系统使PaLM能够协调分布式
computation for accelerators.
加速器的计算。
We previously mentioned that PaLM is a transformer model.
我们之前提到过PaLM是一个Transformer模型。
A transformer model consists of encoder and decoder.
Transformer模型包括编码器和解码器。
The encoder encodes the input sequence
编码器对输入序列进行编码，
and passes it to the decoder, which
然后将其传递给解码器，解码器
learns how to decode the representations
学会如何解码表示，
We've come a long away from traditional programming
我们已经从传统编程发展到了神经网络和生成模型
to have to hard code the rules for distinguishing a cat--
硬编码区分猫的规则，例如：
likes yarn, catnip.
喜欢：纱线，猫薄荷。
In the wave of neural networks, we
在神经网络浪潮中，我们
could give the network pictures of cats and dogs and ask,
可以给网络提供猫和狗的图片，然后询问，
is this a cat?
这是一只猫吗？
can generate our own content, whether it be text, images,
可以生成自己的内容，无论是文本、图片、
audio, video, or other.
音频、视频还是其他。
For example, models like PaLM, or LaMDA,
例如，像PaLM或LaMDA这样的模型，
or Language Model for Dialogue Applications,
或者用于对话应用的语言模型，
ingest very, very large data from multiple sources
从互联网的多个来源获取大量数据
across the internet and build foundation language models
建立基础语言模型，
whether typing it into a prompt or verbally
无论是输入提示还是口头对话提示。
So when you ask it what's a cat, it
当你问它什么是猫时，它会
can give you everything it has learned about a cat.
告诉你它所学到的关于猫的一切。
Let's compare LLM development using pre-trained models
我们来比较一下使用预训练模型的LLM开发
with traditional ML development.
和传统的ML开发。
First, with LLM development, you don't need to be an expert.
首先，使用LLM开发，你不需要成为专家。
And there is no need to train a model.
也不需要训练模型。
All you need to do is think about prompt design, which
你只需要考虑提示设计，即
is the process of creating a prompt that is clear, concise,
创建清晰、简洁、有信息量的提示。
It is an important part of natural language processing.
自然语言处理的重要部分。
In traditional machine learning, you
在传统的机器学习中，你
need training examples to train a model.
需要训练样本来训练模型。
You also need compute time and hardware.
还需要计算时间和硬件。
Let's take a look at an example of a text generation use case.
让我们看一个文本生成用例。
Question answering, or QA, is a subfield of natural language
问答，或者说QA，是自然语言的一个子领域
processing that deals with the task of automatically answering
处理自动回答的任务
questions posed in natural language.
用自然语言提出的问题。
QA systems are typically trained on a large amount
QA系统通常在大量的
of text and code.
文本和代码上进行训练。
And they are able to answer a wide range of questions,
他们能回答各种问题，
including factual, definitional, and opinion-based questions.
包括事实、定义和观点类问题。
The key here is that you need domain knowledge
关键是需要领域知识
For example, domain knowledge is required
例如，需要领域知识
to develop a question-answering model for customer
来开发客户支持、医疗或供应链的问答模型。
Using generative QA, the model generates free text
使用生成式问答，模型根据上下文直接生成自由文本。
There is no need for domain knowledge.
不需要领域知识。
Let's look at three questions given to Bard,
让我们看看给Bard提出的三个问题，
a large language model chat bot developed by Google AI.
Bard是由谷歌AI开发的大型语言模型聊天机器人。
Question one.
问题一。
"This year's sales are $100,000.
"今年的销售额是100,000美元。
Expenses are $60,000.
支出是60,000美元。
How much is net profit?"
净利润是多少？"
Bard first shares how net profit is calculated, then
Bard首先分享了如何计算净利润，然后
performs the calculation.
进行计算。
Then Bard provides the definition of net profit.
接着Bard给出了净利润的定义。
Here's another question.
这是另一个问题。
Inventory on hand is 6,000 units.
现有库存为6,000个单位。
A new order requires 8,000 units.
新订单需要8,000个单位。
How many units do I need to fill to complete the order?
我需要补充多少单位才能完成订单？
Again, Bard answers the question by performing the calculation.
巴德再次通过计算回答了这个问题。
And our last example, we have 1,000 sensors
在我们的最后一个例子中，我们有1,000个传感器
in 10 geographic regions.
分布在10个地理区域。
How many sensors do we have on average in each region?
每个区域平均有多少个传感器？
Bard answers the question with an example
巴德用一个例子回答了这个问题
on how to solve the problem and some additional context.
解决问题的方法和一些额外的背景。
In each of our questions, a desired response was obtained.
在我们的每个问题中，都得到了期望的回答。
This is due to prompt design.
这是因为提示设计（Prompt design）。
Prompt design and prompt engineering
提示设计和提示工程（Prompt Engineering）
are two closely-related concepts in natural language processing.
是自然语言处理中密切相关的两个概念。
Both involve the process of creating
两者都涉及创建
a prompt that is clear, concise, and informative.
一个清晰、简洁、有信息量的提示。
However, there are some key differences between the two.
然而，两者之间存在一些关键差异。
is tailored to the specific task that this system is
它针对的是这个系统正在
being asked to perform.
执行的特定任务。
For example, if the system is being
例如，如果系统正在
asked to translate a text from English to French,
被要求将文本从英语翻译成法语，
the prompt should be written in English
提示应该用英语写
and should specify that the translation should
并且应该指定翻译应该用法语。
Prompt engineering is the process
提示工程是一个过程
of creating a prompt that is designed
旨在创建有助于提高性能的提示
This may involve using domain-specific knowledge,
这可能涉及使用特定领域的知识，
providing examples of the desired output,
提供期望输出的示例，
or using keywords that are known to be
或使用已知对特定系统有效的关键词。
Prompt design is a more general concept,
提示设计是一个更通用的概念，
while prompt engineering is a more specialized concept.
而提示工程则是一个更专业的概念。
Prompt design is essential, while prompt engineering
提示设计至关重要，而提示工程
is only necessary for systems that
只对需要高度准确性或性能的系统才是必要的。
There are three kinds of large language models,
有三种类型的大型语言模型，
generic language models, instruction tuned,
通用语言模型、指令调优、
and dialogue tuned.
和对话调优。
Each needs prompting in a different way.
每种都需要用不同的方式提示。
Generic language models predict the next word
通用语言模型根据训练数据中的语言预测下一个词，
based on the language in the training data.
基于训练数据中的语言。
This is an example of a generic language model.
这是一个通用语言模型的例子。
In this example, "the cat sat on,"
在这个例子中，"the cat sat on,"
And you can see that "the" is the most likely next word.
你可以看到"the."是最可能的下一个词。
Think of this type as an autocomplete in search.
把这种类型想象成搜索中的自动补全。
In instruction tuned, the model is
在指令调整中，模型被训练成
trained to predict a response to the instructions
根据输入的指令预测响应。
For example, summarize a text of X,
例如，总结某某文章中的文本，
generate a poem in the style of X,
以某某的风格创作一首诗，
And in this example, classify the text
在这个例子中，将文本分类为
into neutral, negative, or positive.
中性、消极或积极。
In dialogue tuned, the model is trained to have a dialogue
在对话调整中，模型被训练成通过下一个回应来进行对话。
of instruction tuned where requests are typically framed
指令调优通常是将请求构建成
as questions to a chat bot.
与聊天机器人的问题。
in the context of a longer back and forth conversation,
较长的来回对话中发挥作用，
and typically works better with natural question-like
通常更适合自然的类似问题的表述。
Chain of thought reasoning is the observation
思维链推理（Chain of thought reasoning）是指观察到到的一种现象：
that models are better at getting the right answer when
如果让模型先解释答案的原因，
Let's look at the question.
我们来看这个问题。
Roger has five tennis balls.
罗杰有五个网球。
He buys two more cans of tennis balls.
他又买了两罐网球。
Each can has three tennis balls.
每罐有三个网球。
How many tennis balls does he have now?
现在他有多少个网球？
This question is posed initially with no response.
这个问题一开始没有回答。
The model is less likely to get the correct answer directly.
模型直接得出正确答案的可能性较小。
However, by the time the second question is asked,
但到了第二个问题时，
the output is more likely to end with the correct answer.
输出更有可能得出正确答案。
A model that can do everything has practical limitations.
一个能做所有事的模型在实际应用中是有局限性的。
Vertex AI provides task-specific foundation models.
Vertex AI提供针对特定任务的基础模型。
Let's say you have a use case where
假设你有一个用例，
you need to gather sentiments, or how
你需要收集情绪，或者了解
your customers are feeling about your product or service.
你的客户对你的产品或服务的感受。
You can use the classification task
你可以使用分类任务
sentiment analysis task model.
情感分析任务模型。
If you need to perform occupancy analytics,
如果你需要进行占用率分析
there is a task-specific model for your use case.
那么有一个特定于你用例的任务模型。
Tuning a model enables you to customize the model response
调优一个模型可以让你根据
你希望模型执行的任务的示例来定制模型的响应。
It is essentially the process of adapting a model
本质上，它是通过在新数据上训练模型，
to a new domain, or set of custom use cases,
将模型适应到新的领域，
by training the model on new data.
或一套自定义的用例集合的过程。
For example, we may collect training data
例如，我们可以收集训练数据
and tune the model specifically for the legal or medical
并针对法律或医学领域专门调整模型。
You can also further tune the model by fine tuning
你还可以通过微调进一步调整模型
where you bring your own data set
在这里你可以用自己的数据集
and retrain the model by tuning every weight in the LLM.
并通过调整LLM中的每个权重来重新训练模型。
This requires a big training job and hosting
这需要大规模的训练工作，
your own fine-tuned model.
以及托管你自己微调过的模型。
Here's an example of a medical foundation model trained
比如，这里有一个由医疗数据训练出的医疗基础模型，
The tasks include question answering, image analysis,
其任务包括问答，图像分析，寻找相似患者等等。
Fine tuning is expensive and not realistic in many cases.
但是，微调的费用高昂，在许多情况下并不现实。
So are there more efficient methods of tuning?
那么，有没有更高效的调整方法呢？
Yes.
是的。
Parameter-efficient tuning methods, or PETM,
参数效率调整方法，或称为PETM，
are methods for tuning a large language
是在不复制模型的情况下调整大型语言模型
model on your own custom data without duplicating the model.
的方法，而无需复制模型。
The base model itself is not altered.
基础模型本身并没有改变，
Instead, a small number of add-on layers
只是调整了少数几层附加层，
are tuned, which can be swapped in and out at inference time.
这些层可以在推理时交换。
Generative AI Studio lets you quickly explore and customize
生成式AI工作室让你能快速探索和定制
leverage in your applications on Google Cloud.
可在Google Cloud上用于你的应用的生成式AI模型。
Generative AI Studio helps developers create and deploy
生成式AI工作室帮助开发者通过提供
各种工具和资源创建和部署生成式AI模型，
make it easy to get started.
使得入门变得简单。
For example, there's a library of pre-trained models,
例如，它提供了预训练模型库、
a tool for fine tuning models, a tool for deploying models
用于精细调整模型的工具、用于将模型部署到生产环境的工具，
to production, and a community forum for developers
它提供了预训练模型库、以及供开发者分享想法和合作的社区论坛。
Generative AI App Builder lets you
生成式AI应用构建器让你
create Gen AI apps without having to write any code.
无需编写任何代码就能创建Gen AI应用。
Gen AI App Builder has a drag-and-drop interface
Gen AI应用构建器具有拖放界面
that makes it easy to design and build
使设计和构建应用变得简单，
apps, a visual editor that makes it easy to create and edit
一个可视化编辑器，方便创建和编辑
app content, a built-in search engine that allows users
应用内容，一个内置搜索引擎，允许用户
to search for information within the app,
在应用内搜索信息，
and a conversational AI engine that
以及一个会话式AI引擎，
allows users to interact with the app using natural language.
允许用户使用自然语言与应用进行交互。
You can create your own chat bots, digital assistants,
你可以创建自己的聊天机器人、数字助手、
and more.
等等。
with Google's large language models and Gen AI tools.
谷歌的大型语言模型和 Gen AI 工具。
developers can integrate PaLM API with Maker Suite
开发者可以将 PaLM API 与 Maker Suite 集成
and use it to access the API using a graphical user
并通过图形用户界面访问 API。
The suite includes a number of different tools
该套件包括许多不同的工具，
such as a model-training tool, a model-deployment tool,
如模型训练工具、模型部署工具、
The model-training tool helps developers train ML models
模型训练工具帮助开发者用不同算法训练机器学习模型在他们的数据上。
to production with a number of different deployment options.
将机器学习模型部署到生产环境。
And the model-monitoring tool helps
模型监控工具则帮助
developers monitor the performance of their ML models
开发者通过仪表盘和多种指标
in production using a dashboard and a number
监控生产环境中机器学习模型的性能。
That's all for now.
目前就是这些。
Thanks for watching this course, Introduction to Large Language
感谢收看本课程，大型语言模型简介。